<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">lab3</string>
    <string name="collection_name">30 Days to Financial Freedom</string>
    <string name="day_format">Day %d</string>

    <string name="day1_title">Track Your Expenses</string>
    <string name="day1_text">Start recording every expense, no matter how small</string>
    <string name="day1_full_text">Financial literacy begins with understanding where your money actually goes. Today, start tracking every single expense — coffee, transportation, snacks, subscriptions. Use a notebook, spreadsheet, or mobile app. Don\'t try to change your habits yet; just observe and record. This data will become the foundation of your financial plan.</string>

    <string name="day2_title">Audit Your Subscriptions</string>
    <string name="day2_text">Identify and cancel unused recurring payments</string>
    <string name="day2_full_text">Review your bank statement from the last month and identify all recurring payments — streaming services, apps, gym memberships, insurance. Which ones do you actually use? Cancel any subscriptions that are no longer needed or were forgotten after a free trial. This immediate action puts money back in your pocket starting next month.</string>

    <string name="day3_title">Calculate Small Daily Costs</string>
    <string name="day3_text">Discover the true annual cost of your daily habits</string>
    <string name="day3_full_text">Small daily expenses add up to significant amounts over time. Calculate how much you spend on items like coffee, cigarettes, snacks, or bottled water each day. Multiply this amount by 365 to see the annual cost. Write down this number — it will serve as motivation when you consider optimizing these habits in the future.</string>

    <string name="day4_title">Use What You Have</string>
    <string name="day4_text">Cook a meal using only ingredients already at home</string>
    <string name="day4_full_text">Inspect your refrigerator and kitchen cabinets. Check expiration dates and identify ingredients that need to be used soon. Today, prepare all your meals exclusively from what you already have at home. Avoid ordering food or going to the grocery store. This practice reveals how much food is wasted and how much money can be saved through better planning.</string>

    <string name="day5_title">Set Financial Goals</string>
    <string name="day5_text">Define your short, medium, and long-term financial objectives</string>
    <string name="day5_full_text">Clear goals give direction to your financial decisions. Write down three types of goals:\n\n1. Short-term (up to 1 year): vacation, new phone, emergency fund\n2. Medium-term (1-5 years): car, home down payment, education\n3. Long-term (5+ years): retirement, apartment, children\'s education\n\nNext to each goal, estimate the amount of money required in today\'s prices.</string>

    <string name="day6_title">Calculate Your Net Worth</string>
    <string name="day6_text">Determine your financial position by balancing assets and liabilities</string>
    <string name="day6_full_text">Net worth is the clearest measure of your financial health. List all your assets: cash, bank balances, investments, current value of property and vehicles. Then list all liabilities: credit card debt, loans, mortgages. Subtract liabilities from assets. This number — positive or negative — is your starting point. Track it monthly to measure progress.</string>

    <string name="day7_title">Analyze Your First Week</string>
    <string name="day7_text">Review seven days of expenses and identify patterns</string>
    <string name="day7_full_text">Open your expense records from the past week. Categorize your spending — food, transport, entertainment, utilities. Identify the three largest expense categories and the three most unnecessary purchases. Don\'t judge yourself; simply observe. Understanding your spending patterns is the first step toward intentional financial management.</string>

    <string name="day8_title">Create an Emergency Fund</string>
    <string name="day8_text">Open a dedicated savings account for unexpected situations</string>
    <string name="day8_full_text">An emergency fund is your financial safety net for job loss, medical issues, or urgent repairs. Open a separate savings account — ideally with interest and without a linked card for easy spending. Deposit any amount today, even if it\'s just a small symbolic sum. The goal is to eventually accumulate 3-6 months of essential expenses.</string>

    <string name="day9_title">Switch to Cash</string>
    <string name="day9_text">Use only cash for all purchases today</string>
    <string name="day9_full_text">Psychological studies show people spend less when paying with physical money rather than cards. Today, leave your credit and debit cards at home. Withdraw enough cash to cover planned expenses. Paying with bills and coins makes each transaction more tangible and reduces impulse purchases.</string>

    <string name="day10_title">Review Your Tariffs</string>
    <string name="day10_text">Call your providers and request better rates</string>
    <string name="day10_full_text">Mobile operators and internet providers rarely automatically reduce prices for loyal customers. Contact your service providers and ask: \"Are there any cheaper tariffs available? I\'m considering switching if better options exist.\" Statistics show this simple call results in discounts or better rates in approximately 80% of cases. The savings require just 10 minutes of your time.</string>

    <string name="day11_title">Apply the 24-Hour Rule</string>
    <string name="day11_text">Wait 24 hours before making any non-essential purchase</string>
    <string name="day11_full_text">Impulse purchases are often regretted later. Implement the 24-hour rule: when you want to buy something non-essential above a certain amount (set your own threshold, e.g., $30), wait a full day before purchasing. After 24 hours, reassess whether you truly need the item. Most impulse desires fade, and your money stays where it belongs — in your pocket.</string>

    <string name="day12_title">Review Insurance Coverage</string>
    <string name="day12_text">Check your insurance policies for gaps or overlaps</string>
    <string name="day12_full_text">Insurance protects you from major financial losses. Take inventory of your current insurance: health insurance (including employer-provided), travel insurance, property insurance, life and health insurance. Assess whether coverage is sufficient and eliminate overlapping risks. If you engage in extreme sports, consider expanding your coverage.</string>

    <string name="day13_title">Optimize Cashback</string>
    <string name="day13_text">Configure your cashback categories for maximum returns</string>
    <string name="day13_full_text">Most banks offer cashback programs with selectable priority categories. Open your banking app and set higher cashback percentages for your largest expense categories — groceries, gas stations, pharmacies. Also check cashback services and coupon aggregators before making online purchases. These small percentages add up over time.</string>

    <string name="day14_title">Make Your Second Emergency Fund Contribution</string>
    <string name="day14_text">Transfer another amount to your emergency fund</string>
    <string name="day14_full_text">Consistency matters more than amount. Transfer 1-3% of your weekly income to the emergency fund you opened on Day 8, or any fixed amount that doesn\'t strain your budget. The key is regularity — building a sustainable financial habit. Every contribution, no matter how small, strengthens your financial safety net.</string>

    <string name="day15_title">List All Debts</string>
    <string name="day15_text">Create a complete inventory of your liabilities</string>
    <string name="day15_full_text">Effective debt management requires complete information. Create a structured list of all obligations: credit cards (with balance and grace period), personal loans, mortgages, debts to individuals. For each item, note: total remaining balance, interest rate, monthly payment, and final repayment date. This clarity is the first step toward becoming debt-free.</string>

    <string name="day16_title">Apply the Avalanche Method</string>
    <string name="day16_text">Prioritize paying off your highest-interest debt first</string>
    <string name="day16_full_text">The avalanche method is mathematically optimal for debt repayment. From your Day 15 list, identify the debt with the highest interest rate — typically credit card debt. If possible, pay more than the minimum on this debt today, even if just a small additional amount. Continue making minimum payments on all other debts. This approach minimizes total interest paid over time.</string>

    <string name="day17_title">Sell Unused Items</string>
    <string name="day17_text">Turn clutter into cash by selling unused possessions</string>
    <string name="day17_full_text">Items unused for over a year lose their utility and occupy space without benefit. Walk through your home and select 3-5 items for sale — clothing, electronics, books, collectibles. Photograph them and list on online marketplaces. Price slightly below average for quick sale. Direct all proceeds to your emergency fund or toward your highest-interest debt.</string>

    <string name="day18_title">Identify Side Income Opportunities</string>
    <string name="day18_text">Analyze your skills that could generate additional income</string>
    <string name="day18_full_text">Expense optimization has natural limits, while income potential is bounded only by time and skills. Inventory your professional and practical abilities that might be marketable: tutoring, consulting, repair work, crafts, photography. List at least three potential directions for generating additional income. Sometimes your hobby can become a revenue stream.</string>

    <string name="day19_title">Reframe Your Credit Card Mindset</string>
    <string name="day19_text">Stop viewing credit limits as your own money</string>
    <string name="day19_full_text">Credit cards are often perceived as extensions of personal funds, leading to uncontrolled debt growth. Change your mental model: consider your credit limit non-existent or as an emergency-only resource. Make purchases exclusively with debit cards backed by your own money. If using credit cards for rewards, pay the full balance immediately within the grace period.</string>

    <string name="day20_title">Check Your Credit History</string>
    <string name="day20_text">Obtain your free credit report</string>
    <string name="day20_full_text">Your credit history affects your ability to obtain loans and their terms. Every citizen is entitled to one free credit report per year. Request your report through government services or directly from credit bureaus. If you find errors or signs of fraudulent activity, immediately begin the dispute process. Regular monitoring protects your financial reputation.</string>

    <string name="day21_title">Make an Extra Emergency Fund Contribution</string>
    <string name="day21_text">Add a larger amount to your savings this week</string>
    <string name="day21_full_text">Week three concludes with an enhanced contribution. Transfer up to 5% of your weekly income to your emergency fund. Add any proceeds from item sales (Day 17). This action demonstrates the combined effect of expense optimization and additional income generation. Your growing safety net provides increasing peace of mind.</string>

    <string name="day22_title">Learn Investment Basics</string>
    <string name="day22_text">Understand the difference between stocks, bonds, and ETFs</string>
    <string name="day22_full_text">Investing requires understanding basic asset classes. Study the characteristics of:\n\n1. Stocks: equity securities representing company ownership, offering dividends and capital growth\n2. Bonds: debt securities (government or corporate) returning principal with fixed coupon payments\n3. ETFs: exchange-traded funds providing instant diversification through bundled securities\n\nToday\'s goal is theoretical knowledge only — no transactions required.</string>

    <string name="day23_title">Open an Investment Account</string>
    <string name="day23_text">Create the infrastructure for future investing</string>
    <string name="day23_full_text">For residents with taxable income, an Individual Investment Account offers tax advantages when holding investments for at least three years. Open such an account with a broker or management company associated with major banks. A minimum deposit (often starting from 1,000 rubles) activates the account. You\'ve now created the vehicle for long-term wealth building.</string>

    <string name="day24_title">Create a Detailed Financial Plan</string>
    <string name="day24_text">Calculate required monthly savings for each goal</string>
    <string name="day24_full_text">Transform your Day 5 goals into operational targets. For each goal, divide the target amount by the number of months until achievement. This calculation reveals required monthly savings. If the amount exceeds current capacity, either extend the timeline or reduce the goal\'s scope. Concrete numbers make abstract goals achievable.</string>

    <string name="day25_title">Use the Large Bill Technique</string>
    <string name="day25_text">Leverage psychology to control cash spending</string>
    <string name="day25_full_text">People are psychologically reluctant to break large bills. Withdraw cash as one large denomination. Place all coins and small bills into a savings jar. In daily transactions, avoid breaking the large bill whenever possible. When the jar fills, deposit the accumulated coins into your savings account. This behavioral trick turns pocket change into savings.</string>

    <string name="day26_title">Optimize Gift Giving</string>
    <string name="day26_text">Choose meaningful presents that don\'t strain your budget</string>
    <string name="day26_full_text">Gift expenses can significantly impact budgets, especially during holidays. When planning presents, consider:\n\n1. Handmade gifts (food, services, organized experiences)\n2. Collective gifts with friends for truly needed items\n3. Experience-based gifts rather than material objects\n\nThis approach maintains relationship quality while reducing financial pressure.</string>

    <string name="day27_title">Automate Your Savings</string>
    <string name="day27_text">Set up automatic transfers to your savings account</string>
    <string name="day27_full_text">The most effective saving method removes human discretion. In your banking app, configure automatic recurring transfers from your primary card to your savings account or investment account. Schedule transfers for payday. Set the amount based on your Day 24 calculations. Money moves before you see it, eliminating the temptation to spend.</string>

    <string name="day28_title">Practice Intentional Refusal</string>
    <string name="day28_text">Say no to unplanned spending opportunities</string>
    <string name="day28_full_text">The environment constantly generates spending triggers — marketing promotions, restaurant invitations, spontaneous purchases. Today, practice conscious refusal of such offers when they don\'t align with your financial priorities. This exercise strengthens discipline and reinforces your ability to control financial behavior rather than react to external stimuli.</string>

    <string name="day29_title">Evaluate Your Emergency Fund</string>
    <string name="day29_text">Calculate current savings and project completion timeline</string>
    <string name="day29_full_text">Review your emergency fund balance after 29 days. Compare the current amount to your target (3-6 months of essential expenses). Divide the target by your average monthly savings rate to determine a realistic timeline for full funding. This calculation serves as a long-term motivation tool and confirms your progress.</string>

    <string name="day30_title">Celebrate and Plan Forward</string>
    <string name="day30_text">Review achievements and integrate new habits</string>
    <string name="day30_full_text">Congratulations on completing the 30-day financial literacy course. You have established:\n\n1. Expense tracking and regular budget analysis\n2. An emergency fund (initial stage)\n3. Structured financial goals\n4. Debt management understanding\n5. Basic investment knowledge\n\nDocument your results in writing and schedule your next financial review (3 or 6 months). Convert practiced routines into permanent habits. As a concluding reward, allow yourself a controlled purchase aligned with your budget — you\'ve earned it.</string>
</resources>